Effry Muhammad

Data and Machine Learning Specialist

Surabaya, Indonesia | Phone: +6288803146890 | Email: eff.muhammad@gmail.com

Projects and Portfolio: https://effmuhammad.github.io

SUMMARY

A data and machine learning specialist who has been in this field for 2 years. Have strong programming skills such as Python, C, SQL to manipulate data and extract insightful information. Experienced in doing predictive analytics using python and deep learning. Able to work with various analytics tools and query platform. Kominfo-DQLab "Data Analyst" Professional Academy Certified. Check my work on the portfolio link above.

EXPERIENCE

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya - Surabaya, Indonesia

Artificial Intelligence Researcher [Part-Time] (December 2021 – present)

- Doing research on "Electricity Usage Predictive Analytics with LSTM-RNN Deep Learning Method for Energy Efficiency"
- Have worked on several IoT, Computer Vision and AI projects with Lecturers

PT SARI MAS PERMAI - Surabaya, Indonesia

Electronics and Instrumentation Engineer (November 2020 – May 2022)

- Lead the development of various embedded system improvement with C programming.
- Collaborate with teams from each engineering department to ensure all of factory plant is working well.
- Analyze the electricity usage of each production plant.

EDUCATION

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya (Final Semester, Employee Class)

Bachelor of Applied Science (BASc) of Electronics Engineering

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya (2017 - 2020)

Associate's Degree (D3) of Electronics Engineering - GPA 3.23

TRAINING

- Kominfo-DQLab "Data Analyst" Professional Academy
- Google Cloud Platform QWIKLABS Training
- Dicoding Machine Learning Training
- Dicoding Data Visualization Training
- Dicoding Python Training

SKILL

- Python
- C/C++
- SQL
- Machine Learning
- Data Manipulation
- Data Visualization
- Data Analysis
- Data Analytics
- BigQuery
- Google Analytics
- Firebase
- Automation

ACHIEVEMENT

- 3rd Place in The Innovation Competition by PT Medion Farma Jaya (2020)
- 1st Place in The Infex Cardboard Creativity Competition (2019)
- Kaltim Tuntas Scholarship Awardee (2019 2020)
- PPA Scholarship Awardee (2018-2019)